welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to episode
132 of the listening Time Podcast thank
you all for listening I hope that your
English learning is going great I hope
that you feel motivated to continue on
with your listening practice and keep on
doing what you're doing and just trust
that you're improving even if the
process seems slow uh I want to
encourage you uh to keep on going and
thank you for listening and using this
podcast as one of your tools to help you
with your English uh today I'm going to
talk about a really interesting topic
that I think is relevant to every single
one of us uh the topic is introverts and
extroverts you've probably heard these
words before and I'll talk a little bit
more in detail about these things uh in
just a minute uh but the topic of
introverts and extroverts is really
interesting because it's related to us
our
personality how we uh interact with
other people how we feel about
ourselves and our environments depending
on if you're an introvert or an
extrovert uh this has a lot of influence
over your life so I think this is a very
important topic to talk about and so I'm
excited for this one today before we get
started remember to sign up for my us
conversations podcast if you feel ready
to start
practicing with real conversations so
that you can take your listening to the
next level uh the link is down below
that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you want my
specialized training to help you listen
better and pronounce better and if you
want my Advanced podcast episodes then
make sure to check out my membership and
you can become a listening time Family m
remember uh if you want those Advanced
episodes in particular the link is also
down below that's
patreon.com listeningtime and if you
like this podcast please share it please
send it to your friends or your family
members uh who might benefit from it and
please give it a five-star rating and
wrer review if you can all right let's
get started
are your ears ready you know what time
it is it's listening
time okay let's talk about introverts
and extroverts we're also going to talk
about one other type of person an
ambt uh we'll get into that later but
most people are just familiar with
introverts and extroverts these two ends
of the spectrum remember that when we
talk about the ends of a spectrum we're
talking about the two opposite extremes
on some scale right so on one end we
have introverts and on the other end we
have extroverts so what is an introvert
well an introvert has many character
characteristics and extroverts do as
well so let me talk about some of them
an introvert is usually
characterized as being someone who is
generally quiet and
reserved uh you don't have to be
extremely quiet or extremely reserved
but in general you're more quiet and
reserved than an extrovert let's say and
when people think of
introverts they usually think uh of
people that can be a little bit shy
around uh people they don't know around
strangers uh the word strangers just
refers to people that you're not
familiar with people you don't know
these are strangers so introverts are
often a little little shy or maybe
really shy around
strangers and they can be shy in group
settings so if there are a lot of people
and uh you're all talking together uh if
you're an introvert you might find it
hard to speak up and be the center of
attention and uh control the
conversation that might be hard for you
if you're an introvert and you're in a
group setting so if you're an introvert
you tend to be a little bit more quiet
or reserved or shy especially around
people you don't know or in large groups
however if you're around people that you
do know and people you feel comfortable
with then you're probably not uh the
same as if you were with uh a group of
strangers let's say uh you're probably
going to seem a lot more social less shy
less reserved around people that you do
know so um in general
introverts uh can be quiet and reserved
however that's more around uh people and
in situation
that are unfamiliar to them right if
you're an introvert that doesn't mean
you're always quiet and reserved right I
want to differentiate there uh another
characteristic of introverts and I think
that this is the biggest one or one of
the biggest ones is that introverts tend
to feel
drained by social
situations when we say that you're
drained by something this means that uh
your energy is uh taken away it
decreases it is depleted it is drained
so uh introverts tend to feel drained by
social situations so after a social
situation you might feel exhausted and
you might feel like you need some alone
time you want to just go home and be by
yourself for a while uh that's a really
common um characteristic of an introvert
uh so that's one of the biggest ones you
tend not to feel super energized and
recharged uh from social situations it's
the opposite uh you feel like you're
you're drained and you need some alone
time afterwards that doesn't mean that
you just don't like social situations
that's not always the case but you just
uh feel exhausted from those uh
situations and you actually get
energized in
solitude Solitude just refers to being
alone so being alone actually energizes
you if you're an introvert you feel like
you're
regaining your energy you feel like your
battery is being charged again that's
another characteristic of
introverts and another trait that
introverts might have is that uh they
tend to process a lot of thoughts in
their head
rather than say things out loud all the
time by the way the word trait just
means characteristic or quality so
introverts have this trait often where
they uh think things through in their
head they're very thoughtful they
process a lot of thoughts uh in their
mind uh they don't uh think out loud as
we might say where they're just uh
talking and saying what comes to their
mind right away and uh they tend to be
uh Analytical in that way that they
think through things
silently um without necessarily talking
so that's another trait and one other
trait of
introverts um which can definitely be a
weak weakness sometimes uh is that uh
introverts often avoid
confrontation introverts often have a
hard time confronting people when they
need to I'm sure a lot of you can
identify with this feeling that when you
have to confront someone in maybe an
uncomfortable
situation um you dread this
uh when someone dreads something this
means that they anticipate something
with fear and negativity so I'm sure
some of you feel this dread when you
have to confront someone and talk to
them about something that's
uncomfortable or something that isn't
right or whatever it can be hard hard
for introverts to do this so that one
can be a weakness because there are many
times when we need to confront people
and so that's going to cause some pain
some anxiety for introverts uh when
those situations arise so that's another
uh
characteristic and how about extroverts
let's talk about extroverts now so
extroverts are generally described as
being
outgoing so when you're outgoing this
means that you're someone who naturally
talks and engages people and is able to
produce
conversation and uh and talk to people
and be social
in a natural way so extroverts tend to
be like this extroverts usually enjoy
social settings and they thrive in
Social settings when you thrive we're
saying that you do really well you
succeed or excel in some area so
extroverts thrive in social settings
usually and extroverts actually enjoy
having this attention of being uh in a
group uh being around other people and
actually having the attention on them
I'm sure if you're an introvert that
sounds crazy to you right because you
probably don't like having the attention
on you you don't like
being the center of attention in a group
of people however extroverts often have
no problem with this extroverts can feel
confident in uh talking and being the
center of attention and they aren't
constantly feeling self-conscious about
themselves and what they're saying
extroverts can thrive uh a lot more in
group settings and being uh in the
spotlight uh being in the spotlight
means that you are the center of
attention so extroverts don't mind being
in the spotlight sometimes so that's a
big difference from introverts of course
and contrary to introverts extroverts
can actually feel energy
ized uh in social
situations they actually feel like
they're getting energy when they're
around other people and talking and
engaging uh maybe even complete
strangers who knows but they can feel
energized by this and uh they don't go
home afterwards and say oh man uh that
was so hard I need to go and be by
myself for 5 hours all right they
probably don't feel like that they feel
that they have been recharged and
energized from that social situation so
extroverts don't need as much Solitude
extroverts don't need to be alone as
much and that can sometimes be uh a
disadvantage of being an extrovert is uh
that sometimes extroverts have trouble
being alone it might be hard for them to
be in solitude and they might feel bad
or
anxious uh when they spend more time
alone so that can sometimes be a
negative not all extroverts feel like
that but some do and so that's something
to be aware of as well and extroverts
can often have many friends they might
have a very large circle of friends and
they uh don't feel anxious about uh the
fact that they have such a big thriving
social life uh it's natural for them and
extroverts uh are often more assertive
so they're not as afraid of
Confrontation as introverts are so
extroverts can be more assertive and
actually be uh more comfortable saying
what they need to say confronting other
people talking about that uncomfortable
topic and just uh confrontation in
general extroverts tend to be more
comfortable with that so that can be a
big advantage of being an extrovert
because you don't have that same anxiety
when it comes to
confrontation and one other trait of
extroverts that is sometimes true not
always but uh this can sometimes be a
weakness is that sometimes certain
extroverts might be more easily
distracted so remember how I talked
about introverts being a little bit
more um quiet and analytical in their
thought process introverts often learn
through
observation and
uh are very thoughtful and spend a lot
of time processing thoughts in their
head um extroverts can do that too but
there's also a tendency for some
extroverts to uh be more distracted
maybe less uh focused and spend less
time um in careful observation in
thoughtful observation so they might uh
be more distracted in certain situations
and might not spend as much time just uh
observing one thing and thinking and
processing one
idea uh they might go from one to the
next right so you might disagree with
that if you're an extrovert because you
might not have that trait but when I was
doing some research online that was one
of the traits that came up was that
extroverts can sometimes uh beat like
that so that might be a negative uh for
some
extroverts and how about the last
category ovts so I talked about
introverts and extroverts being on the
opposite ends of the spectrum but but
there are also amb verts which would
kind of be like in the middle so not
completely introverted and not
completely extroverted they're kind of
in the middle and I think a lot of
people uh fall uh in this category here
a lot of you are probably ambiverts to
some degree and some people might make
the argument that all of us have
extrovert and introvert traits but some
of us are more extroverted and some of
us are more introverted so that might be
valid as well uh but I want to talk
about the category of Amber verts just
to talk about the middle uh ground here
the middle of the scale because in
general
for me if someone were to ask me are you
an introvert or an extrovert I would
100% say introvert I'm definitely more
of an introvert than an extrovert
however if I want to be a little bit
more
specific uh I would say that I'm more of
an
ambt uh I would say that I'm more of a
social introvert that's kind of the
phrase that I prefer because I'm
definitely not an extrovert in general
I'm definitely more of an introvert
however I'm an introvert that can at
times seem like an extrovert and I think
that this is the key uh here when I talk
about being uh an ambt or a social
introvert is that in certain situ
situations we can actually seem like
extroverts so if the context is right we
can start to uh
display a lot of extrovert Tendencies
and
qualities uh but in other situations
we're just classic
introverts so I'm sure some of you might
be able to identify with that that in
general you're an introvert however
there are certain
situations where you suddenly change and
it's like you're an extrovert so
depending on the context the environment
your mood uh the topic that people are
talking about U who is around you
depending on these factors you might
suddenly seem like a complete extrovert
and then afterwards go back to being an
introvert so that's kind of how I feel
there are certain situations in which uh
I feel uh like I want to have more
attention I want to talk I want to
engage people I feel outgoing I feel
energized uh I want to be around these
particular people in this
situation sometimes I actually feel like
that but in general that's not my
natural feeling in general I don't want
to be the center of attention I'm not
the most outgoing person I really enjoy
Solitude I really enjoy being by
myself uh I can be by myself for hours
or days Non-Stop and feel great so
obviously I'm an introvert because an
extrovert wouldn't say that however in
certain
situations it's like uh someone flips a
switch and then I'm an extrovert when we
say that someone flips a switch uh think
of someone turning a light on they're
flipping the light switch and suddenly
it's light so this is a figurative
expression that we use to talk about
something changing in an instant so
sometimes it's like someone flip to
switch and I'm suddenly an extrovert
however even in those
situations after the situation is over
uh after I go home let's say I feel
drained so even when I act and feel like
an extrovert afterwards I want my
solitude I want to be alone so as you
can see I'm not an extrovert but I'm a
social introvert I enjoy uh talking to
people I enjoy conversation I enjoy
social contexts however uh in these
contexts I often feel uh more reserved
uh I feel drained I don't want to be the
center of attention so I'm more
introverted in that sense and what's the
best thing to be is it best to be an
introvert an extrovert an ambt well
there's no best thing of course this is
just uh our personality however I think
it's best for us to understand and
identify what type of person we are and
then focus on the possible weaknesses
that we might have because we're an
introvert or because we're an extrovert
or because we're an ambt uh focus on the
weaknesses the things that can be
difficult for us and try to train in
those areas because you can get better
at certain things
uh if you're an introvert you can train
yourself and get better in Social
settings you can do that and if you're
an extrovert you can train yourself to
enjoy Solitude more so you can get
better in these areas so in summary I
think that there's no best type but we
should all focus on improving our weak
weaknesses in these areas all right I
hope this episode was interesting for
you and it was good practice for your
listening if you feel ready I encourage
you to sign up for my us conversations
podcast so you can practice with real
conversations and actually understand uh
multiple people when they're talking to
each other that's a really important
step in your language learning process
to be able to understand multiple native
speakers talking with each other so go
down and click on the link below to sign
up that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you want my
training to help you become a better
listener uh and to pronounce better then
make sure to sign up for my membership
the link is also down below and if you
like this podcast please sh share it
with anyone else you know who's learning
English and give it a fstar rating and
write a review all right thank you for
listening to this episode and I'll talk
to you on the next episode of listening
[Music]
time